<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Crypto &#8211; Code Express</title>
	<atom:link href="http://localhost/wordpress/category/crypto/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://agnijapal.github.io/code-express</link>
	<description>Express Your Idea Through Coding</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2022 15:06:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>NFT &#8211; Non Fungible Token</title>
		<link>https://agnijapal.github.io/code-express/nft-non-fungible-token/</link>
					<comments>https://agnijapal.github.io/code-express/nft-non-fungible-token/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2022 15:04:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://agnijapal.github.io/code-express/?p=805</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A non-fungible token (NFT) is a non-interchangeable unit of data stored on a blockchain, a form of digital ledger, that can be sold and traded. Types of NFT data units may be associated with digital files such as photos, videos, and audio. Because each token is uniquely identifiable, NFTs differ from blockchain cryptocurrencies, such as &#8230;<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="https://agnijapal.github.io/code-express/nft-non-fungible-token/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">NFT &#8211; Non Fungible Token</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>A non-fungible token (NFT) is a non-interchangeable unit of data stored on a blockchain, a form of digital ledger, that can be sold and traded. Types of NFT data units may be associated with digital files such as photos, videos, and audio. Because each token is uniquely identifiable, NFTs differ from blockchain cryptocurrencies, such as Bitcoin.</p>



<p>NFT ledgers claim to provide a public certificate of authenticity or proof of ownership, but the legal rights conveyed by an NFT can be uncertain. NFTs do not restrict the sharing or copying of the underlying digital files, do not necessarily convey the copyright of the digital files, and do not prevent the creation of NFTs with identical associated files.</p>



<p>NFTs have been used as a speculative asset, and they have drawn increasing criticism for the energy cost and carbon footprint associated with validating blockchain transactions as well as their frequent use in art scams. The NFT market has been compared to a Ponzi scheme.</p>



<p>An NFT is a unit of data, stored on a variety of digital ledger called a blockchain, which can be sold and traded. The NFT can be associated with a particular digital or physical asset (such as a file or a physical object) and a license to use the asset for a specified purpose. An NFT (and, if applicable, the associated license to use, copy, or display the underlying asset) can be traded and sold on digital markets. The extralegal nature of NFT trading usually results in an informal exchange of ownership over the asset that has no legal basis for enforcement, and so often confers little more than use as a status symbol.</p>



<p>NFTs function like cryptographic tokens, but unlike cryptocurrencies such as Bitcoin or Ethereum, NFTs are not mutually interchangeable, and so are not fungible. (While all bitcoins are equal, each NFT may represent a different underlying asset and thus may have a different value.)[8] NFTs are created when blockchains concatenate records containing cryptographic hashes—sets of characters that identify a set of data—onto previous records, creating a chain of identifiable data blocks. This cryptographic transaction process ensures the authentication of each digital file[clarification needed] by providing a digital signature that tracks NFT ownership. Data links that are part of NFT records, that for example may point to details about where the associated art is stored, can be affected by link rot.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://agnijapal.github.io/code-express/nft-non-fungible-token/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>ETHEREUM</title>
		<link>https://agnijapal.github.io/code-express/ethereum/</link>
					<comments>https://agnijapal.github.io/code-express/ethereum/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2022 14:57:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://agnijapal.github.io/code-express/?p=801</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The foundation for our digital future Ethereum is open to everyone.All you need is a wallet to take part. Ethereum is open access to digital money and data-friendly services for everyone – no matter your background or location. It&#8217;s a community-built technology behind the cryptocurrency ether (ETH) and thousands of Applications you can use today &#8230;<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="https://agnijapal.github.io/code-express/ethereum/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">ETHEREUM</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The foundation for our digital future</p>



<p>Ethereum is open to everyone.<br>All you need is a wallet to take part.</p>



<p>Ethereum is open access to digital money and data-friendly services for everyone – no matter your background or location. It&#8217;s a community-built technology behind the cryptocurrency ether (ETH) and thousands of Applications you can use today</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://ethereum.org/static/e7a074a56d991c4f9e65857bafa0f053/20da3/what-is-ethereum.webp" alt=""/></figure>



<h2>ETHEREUM 101</h2>



<p>Ethereum is a technology that lets you send cryptocurrency to anyone for a small fee. It also powers applications that everyone can use and no one can take down.</p>



<p>It&#8217;s the world&#8217;s programmable blockchain.</p>



<p>Ethereum builds on Bitcoin&#8217;s innovation, with some big differences.</p>



<p>Both let you use digital money without payment providers or banks. But Ethereum is programmable, so you can also use it for lots of different digital assets – even Bitcoin!</p>



<p>This also means Ethereum is for more than payments. It&#8217;s a marketplace of financial services, games and apps that can&#8217;t steal your data or censor you.</p>



<p>So step into the bazaar and give it a try…</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://agnijapal.github.io/code-express/ethereum/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>BAT &#8211; Making Crypto and DeFi accessible and useable for everyone</title>
		<link>https://agnijapal.github.io/code-express/bat-basic-attention-token/</link>
					<comments>https://agnijapal.github.io/code-express/bat-basic-attention-token/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2022 14:00:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://agnijapal.github.io/code-express/?p=785</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Crypto and DeFi are hard to use and the $330 billion digital advertising industry is failing users, publishers and advertisers. With Basic Attention Token and Brave we want to take Crypto to the next 1B users and solve the endemic inefficiencies and privacy violations hobbling the digital ad industry. BAT has seen stunning results since &#8230;<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="https://agnijapal.github.io/code-express/bat-basic-attention-token/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">BAT &#8211; Making Crypto and DeFi accessible and useable for everyone</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-text-align-left">Crypto and DeFi are hard to use and the $330 billion digital advertising industry is failing users, publishers and advertisers. With Basic Attention Token and Brave we want to take Crypto to the next 1B users and solve the endemic inefficiencies and privacy violations hobbling the digital ad industry.</p>



<p>BAT has seen stunning results since its integration into the <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://brave.com/download/" target="_blank">Brave browser’s</a> first global private ad platform: <strong>54 million</strong> monthly active users, <strong>16 million</strong> daily active users, 1.4 million verified creators accepting BAT, millions of wallets created, thousands of ad campaigns with leading brands, and growing utility in the most innovative names in blockchain gaming. The results make BAT one of the most, if not the most, successful alt–coin projects to date.For the latest figures, you can visit <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://brave.com/transparency/" target="_blank">brave.com/transparency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://agnijapal.github.io/code-express/bat-basic-attention-token/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
